Now that we have downloaded Python, we are going to download our IDE.
So what is an IDE?
It stands for an integrated development environment.
And what it does is it just makes coding a bit easier.
So it adds the things that we don't really need to see.
It gives us a bunch of functions and other things that just make it a lot more simple and easier to
code.
So for our IDE, we are going to use wing.
There are many different Ides out there, and I'm sure through your coding journey you will learn and
use a whole lot of different ones.
But for our classes we are going to be using wing.
So you need to go to wing web.com/downloads.
Once you're here, you're then going to go to the download button and go to wing 101.
So you see there are a few other options.
Wing 101 is just the free version.
And it has everything that you'll need for definitely while you're starting out coding, but probably
for a good few months or even years.
So now it will automatically bring you to the version that you need for whatever operating system you're
using.
So I'm using a mac, so it's giving me this option.
You just download whatever it has here for you.
So go ahead and click the download button.
It's going to give you some steps which you can read, but I'll also bring you through everything step
by step.
So once it's downloaded here we're just going to click.
Once it's finished up opening it is going to pop up with a window for Mac.
You simply just drag this into here and it will begin the installation process.
For Mac users, once it has finished downloading, we are just going to click into applications.
We then need to search for it.
You see it's over here and I'm going to double click here.
You just say open.
You then just need to click accept.
And now we have it downloaded.
So one thing you just need to check is make sure that whatever it says here is the same version of the
path that you've just downloaded.
Otherwise things won't work.
And if it's not, just contact me and I can help you.
Otherwise, there are lots of forums online that will explain what you do if this isn't the same.
Now we have downloaded and we are almost ready to start coding.